A Guide to the Virginia Tech Alumni Association Alumni Cards, 1875-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Tech Alumni Association Alumni Cards, 1875-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 29e
18.19 Cubic Feet 93 boxes
The Virginia Tech Alumni Associaiton Cards, RG 29e, contains cards and rosters about Virginia Tech alumni from 1875 thru 1970. Items include a variety of biographical data, such as names, graduation years, degree program, addresses, names of spouses and children, military service, and more. Series are based on format and arrangement, and individuals may be identified in one or more series.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Alumni Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to Special Collections in 2016.
Administrative Note
On August 11, 1875, Virginia Tech's first Alumni Association was formed by the twelve members of the first graduating class. In 1891, the Association was reorganized, under a new constitution, and began publishing an Alumni Register. The Association was incorporated on June 23, 1924. In 1964, new bylaws were adopted and the Association became more closely linked with the University. At the same time, the title of Alumni Secretary was changed to Director of Alumni Affairs, then to Executive Director in 1972, and then to Executive Vice-President in 1980. In 1990, the Alumni Association became an official part of the University, associated with the Office of Alumni Relations. The Office for Alumni Relations merged with the offices of University Development and University Relations into the Advancement Division [RG 21] in July 2015.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Tech Alumni Associaiton Cards, RG 29e, contains cards and rosters about Virginia Tech alumni from 1875 thru 1970. Items include a variety of biographical data, such as names, graduation years, degree program, addresses, names of spouses and children, military service, and more. Series are based on format and arrangement, and individuals may be identified in one or more series.
Series I contains alumni cards arranged alphabetically by surname, Series II arranged chronologically by graduation year (N.B. no cards exist for graduation year 1934), and Series III arranged by college and degree program.
Series IV: Assorted Alumni Cards and Forms contains a set of Alumni Registration Cards (possibly gathered from a specific event) that are not in any order and describe alumni from various graduation years and degree programs. There are also blank forms to collect alumni biographical data.
The fifth and final series includes Corps of Cadets Rosters from the 1950s and 1960s, arranged chronoligcally by session year. The rosters include each student's name, class (sophomore, senior, etc.), military rank (Colonel, Major, etc.), whether a person is part of a specific staff (Regimental Staff, Second Battalion Staff, etc.), dormitory or barracks and room number, degree program, ROTC unit, and phone number.
Arrangement
The Virginia Tech Alumni Association Alumni Cards, RG 29e, is arranged into five series:
Series I: Alumni Cards by Surname
Series II: Alumni Cards by Graduation Year
Series III: Alumni Cards by College and Degree Program
Series IV: Assorted Alumni Cards and Forms
Series V: Corps of Cadets Rosters
Adjunct Descriptive Data
V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Alumni Cards, c. 1939-1959, RG 29d
Index Terms
Subjects:
University History; University Archives
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute. Alumni Association; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Alumni Association
Contents List
- Series I: Alumni Cards by Surname
  - Aa - Arth (Box 1)
  - Artm - Ba (Box 2)
  - Be - Bols (Box 3)
  - Bolt - Brown, N. (Box 4)
  - Brown, O. - Campbell, M. (Box 5)
  - Campbell, P. - Clark, F. (Box 6)
  - Clark, G. - Coul (Box 7)
  - Coun - Davis, E. (Box 8)
  - Davis, F. - Drake (Box 9)
  - Drap - Este (Box 10)
  - Esti - Fos (Box 11)
  - Fou - Gile (Box 12)
  - Gilh - Gri (Box 13)
  - Gro - Harris, J. (Box 14)
  - Harris, K. - Hile (Box 15)
  - Hill - Hudg (Box 16)
  - Hudk - Jack (Box 17)
  - Jaco - Kelly, P. (Box 18)
  - Kelly, R. - Lamb (Box 19)
  - Lamo - Liu (Box 20)
  - Liv - Martin, H. (Box 21)
  - Martin, J. - McL (Box 22)
  - McM - Monk (Box 23)
  - Mono - Nek (Box 24)
  - Nel - Palmer, E. (Box 25)
  - Palmer, F. - Pi (Box 26a)
  - Pl - Q (Box 26b)
  - R - Rob (Box 26c)
  - Rob - San (Box 27)
  - Sap - Shif (Box 28)
  - Shih - Smu (Box 29)
  - Smy - Sto (Box 30)
  - Str - Thom (Box 31)
  - Thor - Vaw (Box 32)
  - Ve - Web (Box 33)
  - Wed - Williams (Box 34)
  - Williamson - Wy (Box 35)
  - Y - Z (Box 36)
  - Duplicate Cards, A-Z (Box 89)
- Series II: Alumni Cards by Graduation Year
  - 1875 - 1899 (Box 36)
  - 1900 - 1910 (Box 37)
  - 1911 - 1919 (Box 38)
  - 1920 - 1925 (Box 39)
  - 1926 - 1929 (Box 40)
  - 1930 - 1933, (N.B. No cards exist for 1934.) (Box 41)
  - 1935 - 1937 (Box 42)
  - 1938 - 1939 (Box 43)
  - 1940 - 1941 (Box 44)
  - 1942 - 1943 (Box 45)
  - 1943 - 1944 (Box 46)
  - 1945 - 1946 (Box 47)
  - 1946 - 1947 (Box 48)
  - 1948 - 1949 (Box 49)
  - 1950 (Box 50)
  - 1951 (Box 51)
  - 1952 - 1953 (Box 52)
  - 1953 - 1954 (Box 53)
  - 1954 - 1956 (Box 54)
  - 1956 - 1957 (Box 55)
  - 1957 - 1958 (Box 56)
  - 1958 - 1959 (Box 57)
  - 1960 (Box 58)
  - 1961 (Box 59)
  - 1962 (Box 60)
  - 1963 (Box 61)
  - 1963 - 1964 (Box 62)
  - 1964 - 1965 (Box 63)
  - 1965 - 1966 (Box 64)
  - 1966 (Box 65)
  - 1967 (Box 66)
  - 1967 - 1968 (Box 67)
  - 1968 - 1969 (Box 68)
  - 1969 - 1970 (Box 69)
- Series III: Alumni Cards by College and Degree Program
  - College of Agriculture - A - E (Box 70)
  - College of Agriculture - H - P (Box 71)
  - College of Architecture (Box 89)
  - College of Business - Business Administration (Box 72, Box 73)
  - College of Business - B - P (Box 74)
  - College of Environmental Science (Box 74)
  - College of Engineering - Aeronautical - Architectural (Box 75)
  - College of Engineering - B - Chemical (Box 76)
  - College of Engineering - Chemical - Civil (Box 77)
  - College of Engineering - Civil (Box 78)
  - College of Engineering - Commercial - Electrical (Box 79)
  - College of Engineering - Electrical (Box 80)
  - College of Engineering - Electrical - Mechanical (Box 81)
  - College of Engineering - Mechanical (Box 82, Box 83)
  - College of Engineering - Mechanical - Urban and Regional Planning (Box 84)
  - College of Liberal Arts and Human Sciences (Box 85)
  - College of Science - B - Chemistry (Box 86)
  - College of Science - Chemistry - M (Box 87)
  - College of Science - P - Z (Box 88)
- Series IV: Assorted Alumni Cards and Forms
  - Alumni Registration Cards (unordered) (Box 89)
  - Blank Alumni Biographical Data Forms (Box 91, Folder 5)
- Series V: Corps of Cadets Rosters
  - 1953-1954 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - undated (Box 91, Folder 4)